if you're looking to throw some weight
around your home gym well you might want
to consider getting yourself a pair of
bumper plates my friend not only are
they wrapped in rubber it's going to
decrease the chances of ruining your
sanctuary but they're also going to
allow you to do certain exercises where
the barbell tends to be dropped onto the
ground i've been using these slick again
faster bumper plates for a few weeks so
now i'm going to share my findings with
you guys
what's up everybody it's jake back in
the barbie garage gym and in for review
today i've got the again faster bumper
plates in this video i'm going to tell
you everything you need to know about
these bumper plates from the price some
features pros and cons and of course who
should or maybe should not add these to
their home gym before we get started i
have to let you know we've reviewed a
lot of bumper plates on barbin.com
and if you want to explore our best list
just search barbind best bumper plates
and you can find out for yourself which
ones we like the best
okay so what do i like about these
bumper plates well for starters they're
available in individual pairs as well as
full sets so individual pairs come in 10
15 25 35 and 45 pound options and the
full sets are gonna range from 160 up to
a thousand pounds so really there's an
option out there for everybody since
they are in fact bumper plates they're
coated in rubber so this is really nice
especially for at-home usage it's going
to decrease the chance of ruining your
floors as well as protecting the barbell
from damage in those exercises where it
tends to be dropped these are wrapped in
a virgin rubber coating so it's really
going to add on to that durability and
the collar is coat molded which
essentially means that it was fused to
the coating so it's one big piece a
pretty cool thing here is these are
actually approved for the army combat
fitness test which is pretty cool in my
opinion and they also have a dura meter
rating of 90. that's pretty high the
highest is 100 so it's gonna really add
on to that durability it's gonna prevent
them from breaking over time and the
steel inserts are made from 304 steel
this is one of the most commonly found
forms of steel due to its high level
resistance from rust
all right so there are a couple issues
that you might potentially run into with
these bumper plates
since they are in fact bumper plates
you're not going to find any handles
here so that could be a little bit
problematic when you're loading or
unloading your barbell as well as
picking them up off the ground could be
a little bit more difficult to pick them
up because you have to get your hands
underneath the plate shouldn't be that
much of an issue for you just something
worth mentioning and once again since
they are bumper plates they're not
olympic plates so they actually don't
meet the standards of the international
weightlifting federation in terms of
thickness all right so for instance a 45
pound olympic plate is 2.1 inches thick
while this 45 pound bumper plate is 2.9
inches thick so if you are an olympic
lifting competitor out there this really
isn't the option for you in terms of
practicing from home you can still all
you can still do all the same exercises
it's just not you know to the standards
of the iwf
one thing i also noticed here is that
these plates do have two seams on the
outer edges and i don't really know if
this is gonna decrease the lifespan of
these plates but it's something worth
mentioning because i did notice it if
it's something you're worried about
i mean you could go and find some plates
that only have one seam in the middle
and there's also some out there that
look like they don't even have a seam so
once again something worth mentioning
and these are considered cost efficient
compared to some of the other brands out
there on the market but let's be honest
no workout equipment is necessarily
cheap right so if these fall out of your
price range you could go and get some
from walmart or something if you want
but odds are those aren't going to last
you very long like these will
okay so i know what you want to hear now
how much are these going to cost me
right all right so since you can
purchase these individual pairs and as a
full set we're going to split this up
let's start with the individual pairs
you're going to find a 10 pound pair to
cost you about 80 bucks the 25s are
about 140
and the 45 pound pair that's gonna be
about 240
now if you were to go and get yourself a
full set it's gonna wind up being the
best way to go in terms of saving money
in the long run so you're gonna have
seven different options to choose from
and as you may assume the cheapest
option is gonna be the 160 pound set
that's going to cost you around 420
bucks
the 450 pound set that's around 930 and
the thousand pound set that's about two
grand
so i know these are a little bit pricey
still and there's an option for everyone
which is nice but they still could fall
out of your price range but it is worth
mentioning that when you go up in the
weight sets they're actually a little
bit cheaper than some competitors like
rogue so compared to the rest of the
market actually getting a pretty good
deal
these are pretty durable and they could
last you up to 10 years
might make the money worth it in my
opinion
all right so let's talk about the build
now with these again faster bumper
plates as i mentioned you do have 304
steel inserts in these plates the
collars are co-molded to the virgin
rubber coating really it's going to
increase the lifespan of these plates
they could last you 10 years maybe even
longer so i did mention these plates do
not meet international weightlifting
federation in terms of thickness but
they do in terms of diameter so all
these plates are going to have diameter
17.7 inches that's not going to change
it's a really nice feature it's going to
allow beginners
to use the lighter plates and get proper
form or movements like a power clean
which is really cool but on the other
hand
the plates are obviously going to be
thicker depending on how heavy you go so
all i have today is the 25 and 45 pound
plates but for reference the 10-pound
plate is an inch thick so
typically 10-pound bumper plates are
like 8 10 of an inch thick so that
durability of that 10-pound plate is
increased and it may even prevent it
bending or tacoing over time
15-pound plates those are 1.1 inch thick
these 25-pound plates are 1.9 inches
thick the 35s are 2.6 inches thick and
these 45 once again those are 2.9 inches
thick you do not have handles on these
bumper plates that's pretty typical when
it comes to bumper plates shouldn't be
that much of an issue
cool thing is as you can see they are
color-coded
now
does it matter if they're color-coded
not really you can go get yourself a
pair of black bumper plates they're not
going to
work any different than these will but
it's nice because you can easily see
which plate is which and know mentally
how heavy that plate is can kind of
memorize it but if you don't really care
for all that you also do have some
really nice big white lettering here i
like the font and it's super easy to
read you can easily pick and choose
which plate you're going to grab
okay and while these are also rounded
the edges are technically flat so this
could be a bit of an issue as you're
going to pick them up off the ground you
know the 25 wasn't that bad but these
45s i will say
i did have a bit of an issue at first it
was laying flat on the ground i went to
go pick it up i couldn't really get a
good grip on it at all so i had to slide
it up against my foot get that extra
leverage and lift it up so you're really
gonna have to focus on getting your
hands underneath these plates
okay so let's talk a little bit more now
about those individual pairs and the
full sets so once again the pairs range
from 10 pounds to 45 pounds and those
full sets are gonna range from 160 to a
thousand pounds
and the weight you get in those full
sets that's gonna vary depending on how
heavy you go with so let's start with
that 160 pound set you're gonna get two
tens two 25s and two 45 pound plates
with your purchase 350 pound set you're
gonna get two tens two 15s 225's 235
and then two 45 pound plates with that
purchase and that thousand pound set
well that's really going to be the
biggest bang for your buck because you
are going to get eight tens 10 15 8 25 6
35 and 8 45 pound plates now i know
that's too grand up front and if you
don't want to do that i completely
understand but like i said it is going
to be the biggest bang for your buck
because if you were to start lighter and
then expand over time you're gonna
actually wind up spending more money
than if you just shelled out that two
grand from the
[Music]
get-go all right let's take a quick walk
around these bumper plates now let's
start with the fact that these are in
fact color-coded as you can see it's
going to be specific to each weight
that's going to make it really easy for
you to pick and choose which one you
want to go with but you know you also
have this big white lettering on both
sides of the plate that's just gonna you
know help you out even more that white
really contrasts with the color of the
plate and i like the big white font as
well just brings a nice aesthetic to it
i like the font that they used the
co-molded collar right here as you look
up close and you kind of put your finger
right here you can't there's really no
seam at all so that's going to increase
that durability and help these last for
a really long time now
as you flip them to the side
you'll see that there are two seams on
the outside now i don't know if that's
going to really decrease the lifespan of
these plates but it's worth mentioning
it and especially since there's some
plates out there that only feature one
seam right down the middle and there's
some that can't even tell that there's a
seam on them now they're obviously
rounded but they also have a squared off
profile and that's what's making them
stand up on their own right now
so with this 25 pound plate i didn't
have any issues when picking it up off
the ground when it was laying flat but
with the 45s i definitely had to slide
it to my foot just to get that extra
leverage to get my hand up underneath it
to pick it up off the ground and that
could be a little bit of an issue for
you but i mean i got the hang of it i'm
sure you can too
all right now the thickness is going to
vary depending on which plate you go
with but the diameters of these plates
are all identical so i'm going to slide
this across right here for you
they meet the international
weightlifting federation standards of
17.7 inches and you know you can't see
this blue one so that's really nice it
goes to show they are in fact the same
diameter but just for the purpose of
this video i do have a tape measure for
you guys so let's go ahead and do that
for y'all
as you can see
it's right there at 17.7 inches so
it backed up what they said
[Music]
okay so who should purchase these again
faster bumper plates well
for somebody out there who's wanting to
ramp up your at-home workouts with some
power cleans these are good options to
consider the virgin rubber is going to
protect the plate itself as well as the
barbell and your floor from any
potential damage the 304 steel inserts
are going to protect the plate over time
and prevent them from bending and since
you do have various buying options in
either individual pairs or full set you
always have the luxury of expanding your
weight over time okay so what about the
people who i don't know maybe should not
purchase these bumper plates well let's
talk about price all right i know these
are considered cost effective compared
to some other brands out there
but they're not really cheap right if
they do fall out of your price range i'm
sure you could go out there and find
some bumper plates they're going to cost
you less than these but you'll probably
have to replace those
sooner than you'd have to replace these
so what you actually wound up spending
more money in the long run yeah
so since these are also bumper plates
once again they don't have handles so if
that's something you just
can't get over then
maybe you just need to get yourself some
traditional plates you might even could
find some urethane plates that have
handles but remember traditional plates
are not meant for the same exercises as
bumper plates are and the urethane might
actually crack so that life span might
be shorter than some bumper plates like
these are and one more thing remember
these are not olympic plates they're
bumper plates so they do not meet the
thickness standards of the international
weightlifting federation so
if you're a competitor out there you're
looking for an option to train from home
yeah you can still use these you can
still do all the same movements but they
are thicker so that's something you
might need to remember when you're going
to make a purchase
all right y'all that's a wrap on today's
review over the again faster evolution
bumper plates i think these are pretty
sweet in my opinion i like the color
coding it looks nice and aesthetic in
our gym
the 304 steel inserts the virgin rubber
coating and the coat molded collars are
really going to add to the durability i
don't have to worry about them bending
and me having to replace them in just a
couple of years
thanks for watching everybody hope this
video was helpful and showed you what
these bumper plates can bring to your
home gym as always stay on the lookout
for my next review but for now why don't
you head over to barbin.com and you can
read more on these bumper plates just
search barbin again faster evolution
bumper plates and you can read
everything we talked about here today in
more detail i'll see you all next time
[Music]
you